<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Dmitriy Savchenko]]></title>
  <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-15T20:01:40+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dmitriy Savchenko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tip: Save document opened in vim without permissions]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/12/15/tip-save-protected-document-openned-in-vim/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T19:47:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/12/15/tip-save-protected-document-openned-in-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This one can save some time for you. How much? It depends on how often you use vim and what you do with it.</p>

<p>Imagine you opened a document im vim and started making changes. Time goes by and you decide to save the document.
And guess what - you do not have permissions to do this. You opened some config in /etc/something but you did this as regular user.</p>

<p>At this point you have several ways to overcome this problem, but I only use this one lately.</p>

<p>All you need is instead of typing</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>:w</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>to save document, type</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>:w sudo tee  %</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Well, I won&#8217;t pretend, at the moment I do not know what this command do exactly, but it helps.
This way you can save document (if you know user password or user do not need one and if user can run sudo command)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[symbol 'grub_term_highlight_color' not found]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/10/21/symbol-grub-term-highlight-color-not-found/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-21T22:42:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/10/21/symbol-grub-term-highlight-color-not-found</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Those lines from title wasn&#8217;t exactly expected to appear after ubuntu 14.04 update.</p>

<p>It all started kinda from the wrong foot when I decided to finally update my home dual boot setup - ubuntu 13.04/win7.</p>

<p>During the update from 13.04 to 13.10 (it isn&#8217;t possible to update from 13.04 to 14.04 - you need to go through all steps)
Dropbox failed to update and I noticed this only when I got home from work in the evening. Day wasted.</p>

<p>But I decided that it wasn&#8217;t a big deal and I simply cancelled distro upgrade.
After reboot I noticed that I already have 13.10. That&#8217;s cool I thought andmoved to upgrade to 14.04 after removing Dropbox.
All went fine and in the end I clicked Reboot now in the modal window.</p>

<p>And that is when I faced black screen with error from title. To make colors darker - I even couldn&#8217;t get to bios when I pressed reboot like 10 times.
Strange behaviour. But then I switched computer off and on and was able to get to bios. Hooray.</p>

<p>Hopefully I have notebook and I was able to google solution for this inconvenience.
As it always happens first solution is to wipe all drives clean and reinstall everything.</p>

<p>No way I said and kept searching.
After some time I found this <a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/449818/cant-find-boot-repair-package-for-the-newest-version-of-ubuntu">link</a> which helped me to solve my problem.</p>

<p>Basically all you need is:</p>

<ul>
<li>to create boot cd (wait what?) or flash stick</li>
<li>boot from it</li>
<li>select &#8220;Try ubuntu&#8221; option (I assume you created ubuntu boot cd/usb)</li>
<li>install boot-repair</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo add-apt-repository ppa:yannubuntu/boot-repair
</span><span class='line'>sudo sh -c "sed -i 's/trusty/saucy/g' /etc/apt/sources.list.d/yannubuntu-boot-repair-trusty.list"
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get update
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get install -y boot-repair && (boot-repair &)</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>As you can see this helpful tool isn&#8217;t available for 14.04 and you need to switch it&#8217;s sources to previous ubuntu version.</p>

<ul>
<li>run</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo boot-repair</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>When tool starts it is quite easy to understand what to do (I selected recommended repair)
After some time it said that all done and I was able to load both new ubuntu and good old win7.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tip: ssh-copy-id alternative]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/09/30/tip-ssh-copy-id-alternative/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-30T00:32:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/09/30/tip-ssh-copy-id-alternative</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This one snippet also start to appear in my search results more often.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>cat ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | ssh -o PubkeyAuthentication=no user@192.168.33.10 "mkdir ~/.ssh; cat &gt;&gt; ~/.ssh/authorized_keys"
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The key part of this one liner is:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>-o PubkeyAuthentication=no</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p> You can&#8217;t specify it for ssh-copy-id and without it you get this error</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>$ Received disconnect from host: 2: Too many authentication failures for user</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p> Also other solutions can be found <a href="http://superuser.com/questions/187779/too-many-authentication-failures-for-username">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tip: Delete git remote tag]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/09/30/tip-delete-git-remote-tag/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-30T00:12:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/09/30/tip-delete-git-remote-tag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a quite long period of time I&#8217;ve been using this method to delete remote tag in git repository:</p>

<ul>
<li>Find myself in a situation when you totally need to remove that pushed tag</li>
<li>Feel frustrated, because even after doing this more than 10 times I still fail to remember the command</li>
<li>Google the command</li>
<li>Click on that purple link - first in search results for &#8220;git delete remote tag&#8221;</li>
<li>Look at the command and feel embarrassed again</li>
<li>Copy paste the command to the terminal window.</li>
</ul>


<p>Today  must admit that I have the problem and the first step to overcome it - add link to solution to this blog:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>git tag -d 12345
</span><span class='line'>git push origin :refs/tags/12345</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><a href="http://nathanhoad.net/how-to-delete-a-remote-git-tag">source</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[VirtualBox guest additions reinstall]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2012/01/07/virtualbox-guest-additions-reinstall/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-07T22:47:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2012/01/07/virtualbox-guest-additions-reinstall</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/GubLdl.jpg"></p>

<p>Software development obviously needs some environment. After some time spent working as developer i&#8217;ve got strong filling,
that this envirement should be separated from my desktop. At least vitrually.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So i am working with server inside VirtalBox. It&#8217;s preaty hendy solution, but lack of exirience can couse some troubles.</p>

<p>For example i have computer with Windows7/Ubuntu 11.10 in dual boot and i really would like to work with
the same virtual mashine from each of the two operating systems. At the time of this writing i didn&#8217;t manage to achieve
this useful functionality, so i keep using Windows more heavily than i want (Thanks Skyrim, shame on me).</p>

<p>Just today i tryed to use ubuntu server virtual mashine, configured to use with windows and encoutered some problems.</p>

<p>So handy advise if you want to use virtual mashine in different operating systes:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Don&#8217;t forget to remove VBoxAdditions disk after additions intallation.
Paths in ubuntu and windows to that disk are equally not acceptable.</p></li>
<li><p>If you, like me, use two adapters to connect virtual mashine to internet (NAT) and to host (Hast only Network) you
probably would be surprized to know, VirtualBox have different names for second one in linux and windows. And, yes,
these names are incompatible too. So after OS chnge you shold go to VM settings and open window with Host only netwoerk
settings. After that name will be change to propper for current OS. (Why have they done this?)</p></li>
</ol>


<p>After that if you have network properly set up - you shouldn&#8217;t fill any differece. All work like clock.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start playing with Zend Framework 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2011/12/31/start-playing-with-zend-framework-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-31T05:08:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2011/12/31/start-playing-with-zend-framework-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Nlro8.png"></p>

<p>New version of framework comes with great deal of changes and still is in beta, but definetly worth looking at.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Some of the biggest chenges are:</p>

<pre><code>- framework start using namespases
- redused number of singletons in project
- framework heavily rely on Dependency Injection(DI) and Dependency Injection Container(DIC)
</code></pre>

<p>To explain this concept there is <a href="http://framework.zend.com/wiki/display/ZFDEV2/Zend+DI+QuickStart">tutorial</a></p>

<p><a href="http://packages.zendframework.com/">packages.zendframework.com</a> is great place to start. There you can in
various ways download and install framework. Also it has usefull links to api, blog and wiki.</p>

<p><a href="http://akrabat.com/zend-framework/updated-tutorial-for-zend-framework-2-beta-1/">Rob Allen&#8217;s (Akrabat) tutorial</a> has been updated
to support first beta of framework. In this tutorial you can create simple catalog app using Zend Framework 2.</p>

<p>Also there you can find link to <a href="https://github.com/zendframework/ZendSkeletonApplication">ZendSkeletonApplication</a> and
way to get application and frameworn in one simple git clone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple static blog using Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2011/11/24/simple-static-blog-using-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-24T00:27:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2011/11/24/simple-static-blog-using-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/NGE2a.png" title="Image tag" ></p>

<p>Comes to end year of owning my first hosting. I win it in New Year contest from Logol on habrahabr.ru.
Nice hosting, but paying even small amount of money for the thing you use one or two times a month
(games twitter and work take almost all my time) is inpractical.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>About half a year ago i&#8217;ve discovered posibility of hosting site on github. Some time latter i tryed heroku - so paying
money for something you can get free - no way.</p>

<p>And at last i&#8217;ve found time to transfer my almost empty wordpress blog to octopress and host it on github. Choosing heroku you
can get private repository for your blog or whatever you what to host there. But it wasn&#8217;t critical for me so here i am on github.</p>

<p>Site is completely static now - just a bunch of html pages generated by Jakyll. And still it has:</p>

<pre><code>* comments thanks to Disqus,
* latest projects from github and tweets,
* code highlight
</code></pre>

<p>What else do i realy need?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
