<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Dmitriy Savchenko]]></title>
  <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-08T00:16:27+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dmitriy Savchenko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[VirtualBox guest additions reinstall]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2012/01/07/virtualbox-guest-additions-reinstall/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-07T22:47:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2012/01/07/virtualbox-guest-additions-reinstall</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/GubLdl.jpg"></p>

<p>Software development obviously needs some environment. After some time spent working as developer i&#8217;ve got strong filling,
that this envirement should be separated from my desktop. At least vitrually.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So i am working with server inside VirtalBox. It&#8217;s preaty hendy solution, but lack of exirience can couse some troubles.</p>

<p>For example i have computer with Windows7/Ubuntu 11.10 in dual boot and i really would like to work with
the same virtual mashine from each of the two operating systems. At the time of this writing i didn&#8217;t manage to achieve
this useful functionality, so i keep using Windows more heavily than i want (Thanks Skyrim, shame on me).</p>

<p>Just today i tryed to use ubuntu server virtual mashine, configured to use with windows and encoutered some problems.</p>

<p>So handy advise if you want to use virtual mashine in different operating systes:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Don&#8217;t forget to remove VBoxAdditions disk after additions intallation.
Paths in ubuntu and windows to that disk are equally not acceptable.</p></li>
<li><p>If you, like me, use two adapters to connect virtual mashine to internet (NAT) and to host (Hast only Network) you
probably would be surprized to know, VirtualBox have different names for second one in linux and windows. And, yes,
these names are incompatible too. So after OS chnge you shold go to VM settings and open window with Host only netwoerk
settings. After that name will be change to propper for current OS. (Why have they done this?)</p></li>
</ol>


<p>After that if you have network properly set up - you shouldn&#8217;t fill any differece. All work like clock.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start playing with Zend Framework 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2011/12/31/start-playing-with-zend-framework-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-31T05:08:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2011/12/31/start-playing-with-zend-framework-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Nlro8.png"></p>

<p>New version of framework comes with great deal of changes and still is in beta, but definetly worth looking at.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Some of the biggest chenges are:</p>

<pre><code>- framework start using namespases
- redused number of singletons in project
- framework heavily rely on Dependency Injection(DI) and Dependency Injection Container(DIC)
</code></pre>

<p>To explain this concept there is <a href="http://framework.zend.com/wiki/display/ZFDEV2/Zend+DI+QuickStart">tutorial</a></p>

<p><a href="http://packages.zendframework.com/">packages.zendframework.com</a> is great place to start. There you can in
various ways download and install framework. Also it has usefull links to api, blog and wiki.</p>

<p><a href="http://akrabat.com/zend-framework/updated-tutorial-for-zend-framework-2-beta-1/">Rob Allen&#8217;s (Akrabat) tutorial</a> has been updated
to support first beta of framework. In this tutorial you can create simple catalog app using Zend Framework 2.</p>

<p>Also there you can find link to <a href="https://github.com/zendframework/ZendSkeletonApplication">ZendSkeletonApplication</a> and
way to get application and frameworn in one simple git clone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple static blog using Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2011/11/24/simple-static-blog-using-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-24T00:27:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2011/11/24/simple-static-blog-using-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/NGE2a.png" title="Image tag" ></p>

<p>Comes to end year of owning my first hosting. I win it in New Year contest from Logol on habrahabr.ru.
Nice hosting, but paying even small amount of money for the thing you use one or two times a month
(games twitter and work take almost all my time) is inpractical.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>About half a year ago i&#8217;ve discovered posibility of hosting site on github. Some time latter i tryed heroku - so paying
money for something you can get free - no way.</p>

<p>And at last i&#8217;ve found time to transfer my almost empty wordpress blog to octopress and host it on github. Choosing heroku you
can get private repository for your blog or whatever you what to host there. But it wasn&#8217;t critical for me so here i am on github.</p>

<p>Site is completely static now - just a bunch of html pages generated by Jakyll. And still it has:</p>

<pre><code>* comments thanks to Disqus,
* latest projects from github and tweets,
* code highlight
</code></pre>

<p>What else do i realy need?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
