<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ubuntu | Dmitriy Savchenko]]></title>
  <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/categories/ubuntu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-21T23:15:46+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dmitriy Savchenko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[symbol 'grub_term_highlight_color' not found]]></title>
    <link href="http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/10/21/symbol-grub-term-highlight-color-not-found/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-21T22:42:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://loginwashere.github.com/blog/2014/10/21/symbol-grub-term-highlight-color-not-found</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Those lines from title wasn't exactly expected to appear after ubuntu 14.04 update.</p>

<p>It all started kinda from the wrong foot when I decided to finally update my home dual boot setup - ubuntu 13.04/win7.</p>

<p>During the update from 13.04 to 13.10 (it isn't possible to update from 13.04 to 14.04 - you need to go through all steps)
Dropbox failed to update and I noticed this only when I got home from work in the evening. Day wasted.</p>

<p>But I decided that it wasn't a big deal and I simply cancelled distro upgrade.
After reboot I noticed that I already have 13.10. That's cool I thought andmoved to upgrade to 14.04 after removing Dropbox.
All went fine and in the end I clicked Reboot now in the modal window.</p>

<p>And that is when I faced black screen with error from title. To make colors darker - I even couldn't get to bios when I pressed reboot like 10 times.
Strange behaviour. But then I switched computer off and on and was able to get to bios. Hooray.</p>

<p>Hopefully I have notebook and I was able to google solution for this inconvenience.
As it always happens first solution is to wipe all drives clean and reinstall everything.</p>

<p>No way I said and kept searching.
After some time I found this <a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/449818/cant-find-boot-repair-package-for-the-newest-version-of-ubuntu">link</a> which helped me to solve my problem.</p>

<p>Basically all you need is:</p>

<ul>
<li>to create boot cd (wait what?) or flash stick</li>
<li>boot from it</li>
<li>select "Try ubuntu" option (I assume you created ubuntu boot cd/usb)</li>
<li>install boot-repair</li>
</ul>


<p><code>
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:yannubuntu/boot-repair
sudo sh -c "sed -i 's/trusty/saucy/g' /etc/apt/sources.list.d/yannubuntu-boot-repair-trusty.list"
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install -y boot-repair &amp;&amp; (boot-repair &amp;)
</code></p>

<p>As you can see this helpful tool isn't available for 14.04 and you need to switch it's sources to previous ubuntu version.</p>

<ul>
<li>run</li>
</ul>


<p><code>
sudo boot-repair
</code></p>

<p>When tool starts it is quite easy to understand what to do (I selected recommended repair)
After some time it said that all done and I was able to load both new ubuntu and good old win7.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
